Working Inventory of the Robert E. Marshak Papers, 1947-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Box D2
  - Scientific Council Meeting-correspondence from John Hall, Paolo Budini, etc.; reports, etc. (Box-folder D2-6)
  - International Atomic Energy Agency 1960-61-correspondence. (Box-folder D2-7)
  - International Centre for Theoretical Physics, including: (Box-folder D2-8)
    - 1. Trieste Center-correspondence from Marshal Rosenbluth, Luciano Vertocchi, H. R. Dalafi, etc.
  - ICTP Council Meeting-correspondence Paolo Budinich, L. Bertocchi; agendas. (Box-folder D2-9)
  - INU-IZ-correspondence from Irving S. Norry, J. F. Detoeuf, D. Invanenko. (Box-folder D2-10)
  - J-JA-scientific notes; correspondence to/from: Dr. M. Jacob, Boris A. Jacobson, etc., including: (Box-folder D2-11)
    - 1. Japan-schedules, correspondence from Yoshio Fujioka, paper/article about Information on Tokyo for U.S. Delegation.
  - JB-JZ-correspondence from Zhang Jianzi, M. H. Johnson, etc. (Box-folder D2-12)
  - K-KEK-correspondence to/from: P. K. Kabir, Malu wa Kalenga, Calvin Kalmon, etc. (Box-folder D2-13)
  - KEL-KN-Charles A. Keller, Armand W. Kelly, etc. (Box-folder D2-14)
- Box E1
  - KO-KZ-correspondence to/from: Kobayashi, Julius Ashkin, Mayor Edward Koch, etc. (Box-folder E1-1)
  - L-LD-correspondence to/from: Parker Ladd, Lansing Lamot, etc.; curriculum vitae for Paul G. Langacker, etc. (Box-folder E1-2)
  - Lee, C. Y.-Correspondence and scientific paper from Ching-Yieh Lee. (Box-folder E1-3)
  - LE-LEVICH-correspondence to/from: T. D. Lee, Edward Levi, etc.; cirriculum vitae for Evgeny Levich. (Box-folder E1-4)
  - LEVIENS-LH-Levien, Raphael: correspondence concering what to do about an eleven year old boy taking senior courses at Virginia Tech, 1981-1984. (Box-folder E1-5)
  - LI-LIO-correspondence to/from: Y. Liang. (Box-folder E1-6)
  - LIP-LOS-correspondence to/from: H. J. Lipkin, Seth Lipsky, etc. (Box-folder E1-7)
  - Los Alamos Reunion;-listing of invited guests; newspapers. (Box-folder E1-8)
  - LOT-LZ-correspondence to/from: Elmer Louis, Arnold N. Loawn, Gungru Lu, etc. (Box-folder E1-9)
  - M-MAR-correspondence from: Zhong-Qi Ma, Frank J. Macchiarola, Richard Medey. etc. (Box-folder E1-10)
  - Maryland APS Meeting-paper by different speakers; scientific notes. (Box-folder E1-11)
  - MAS-MD-correspondence to/from: McGraw Hill Book Company, Inc (Box-folder E1-12)
  - Mexican Symposium-correspondence. (Box-folder E1-13)
  - Mehra visit 1988-correspondence. (Box-folder E1-14)
  - Mehra-correspondence. (Box-folder E1-15)
  - ME-fax; paper, correspondence, etc. (Box-folder E1-16)
  - Miniconference-program, agenda. (Box-folder E1-17)
- Box E2
  - Proposal for American Participation in Phase II of the Neutron Oscillation Experiment at Ill, Grenoble, reports. (Box-folder E2-1)
  - Luke W. Mo-recommended for the Panofsky Prize, works written by Mo, etc. (Box-folder E2-2)
  - MOA-MZ-correspondence to/from: John W. Moffat, R. N. Mohapatra, Michael J. Moravcsik, etc. (Box-folder E2-3)
  - National Academy of Engineering-pamphlet for nomiations. (Box-folder E2-4)
  - N-National-correspondence to/from: Nasser Nafari, M. el Nadi, etc. (Box-folder E2-5)
  - National Research Council of Canada-correspondence concerning the NRCC to/from M.H. Trytten, etc. (Box-folder E2-6)
  - Correspondence concerning proposals for nomination to/from Philip Handler, etc. (Box-folder E2-7)
  - National Academy of Scienes (NAS), including: (Box-folder E2-8)
    - 1. Correspondence from Hans Frauenfelder.
    - 2. High Technology Meeting-report: International Relations in a Technologically Advanced Future by Richard N. Cooper and Ann L. Hollick.
    - 3. Committee on Human Rights (NAS)-correspondence to/from: Lipman Bers, etc.
    - 4. Correspondence on NAS activities.
  - NAS-China-correspondence on Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (1985); eight chapter drafting of Scope of Exchange Study. (Box-folder E2-9)
  - NAS-Foreign Associates (1981)-correspondence to/from: H. H. Barschall, Robert G. Sachs, etc. (Box-folder E2-10)
  - NAS-Proposal for nominations for foreign associates-biographical information. (Box-folder E2-11)
  - NAS-Votes for 1982-proposals for nominations, biographical information, etc. (Box-folder E2-12)
  - NAS-1984 nominating letters. (Box-folder E2-13)
  - NAS-Foreign Associates-proposals for nominatino of foreign associates membership. (Box-folder E2-14)
  - 1986-NAS proposals for nomination of membership. (Box-folder E2-15)
  - 1988-NAS Panel for Foreign Associates. (Box-folder E2-16)
  - 1988-NAS nominations for foreign associates. (Box-folder E2-17)
  - 1989-NAS nominations for foreign associates. (Box-folder E2-18)
  - 1990-NAS correspondence to solicit foreign associates. (Box-folder E2-19)
  - 1991-NAS nomination for foreign associates. (Box-folder E2-20)
  - 1992-NAS soliciting nominations for foreign associates. (Box-folder E2-21)
  - NAS Human Resource-various NAS documents/reports/reviews of national educational policies in science and engineering. (Box-folder E2-22)
  - NAS meeting-pre-registration forms. (Box-folder E2-23)
- Box F1
  - NAS Members-proposals for nominations; a 1985 and 1987 book on election of members; papers on the selection of the screening panel. (Box-folder F1-1)
  - NAS Nominations-proposals for nominations; correspondence concerning nominations. (Box-folder F1-2)
  - NAS Panels-correspondence from Steve Adler, including: (Box-folder F1-3)
    - 1. 1986 Panel-correspondence.
    - 2. 1987-correspondence concerning candidates.
    - 3. 1988-correspondence concerning candidates.
    - 4. 1989-correspondence.
    - 5. 1990-proposals for members.
    - 6. 1991-informal ballot.
    - 7. 1992-correspondence.
  - NAS Proceedings Office. (Box-folder F1-4)
  - National Research Council, including: (Box-folder F1-5)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Melvin Thompson, etc.
  - NAS 1983 Workshop-agenda; notes; list of invited participants; essays/reports. (Box-folder F1-6)
  - National Accelerator Laboratory-correspondence to/from: E. Goldwasser, etc. (Box-folder F1-7)
  - National Association-National Institution, including: (Box-folder F1-8)
    - 1. Minutes of NAM Committee on Research.
    - 2. National Humanities Center-list of names; brochures; booklet.
  - National Science Board-correspondence concerning the names for the nominations. (Box-folder F1-9)
  - Correspondence concerning the proposal for the Nucleon-Nucleon Interaction from Harold S. Zapolsky, etc. (Box-folder F1-10)
  - Correspondence concerning the National Science Foundation. (Box-folder F1-11)
- Box F2
  - National Science Foundation (NSF). (Box-folder F2-1)
  - NB-NH, including: (Box-folder F2-2)
    - 1. Letters to the New York Times
    - 2. Newsletters from Research Division, memorandum, humanities, etc.
  - New York Academy of Science-pamphlet. (Box-folder F2-3)
  - NIG-NIGD-correspondence to/from: Rodney W. Nichols, etc. (Box-folder F2-4)
  - Nigeria-correspondence from Moyibi Amoda; meeting of the Nigera-United States Workshop on Technological Development in Nigeria. (Box-folder F2-5)
  - NIH-NZ, including: (Box-folder F2-6)
    - 1. Nishijima Festschrift-correspondence from Akira Ukawa; paper prepared for Festschrift in honor of Kazuhiko Nishijima.
    - 2. Nobel Prize-names of winners for 1977 in the press release from the Royal Swedish Academy of Science; booklet from 1900-Nobelstiftelse, The Nobel Foundation, Code of Statutes given; listing of winners fron 1980 in physics, chemistry, economt; 1981 for physics, sconomy, chemistry; 1979 in economy and physics.
    - 3. University of North Carolina Evaluation Committee.
    - 4. Nuclear Forces and the Few-Nucleon Problem (conference).
    - 5. Nucleonics-scientific notes, etc.
  - ON-OP, including: (Box-folder F2-7)
    - 1. Correspondence from Yuko Okamoto.
    - 2. Scientific notes and correspondence; booklet entitled "Supplement of the Progress of Theoretical Physics"; correspondence from S. Okubo.
  - Orbis Scientiae, including: (Box-folder F2-8)
    - 1. 1980 correspondence from Arnold Perlmutter; list of participants; papers from 1980 talks.
    - 2. 1981 list of participants; brochure.
  - Oppenheimer 1982-Marshak receives the J. Robert Oppenheimer Memorial Prize. Letters to/from: Robert Oppenheimer. (Box-folder F2-9)
  - OR-OZ, including: (Box-folder F2-10)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from/about Peter Orland.
  - P1071-Physics 1071 (1979). Notes, grades, syllabus, and evaluations. (Box-folder F2-11)
  - P-PAR, including: (Box-folder F2-12)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: M. K. Parida; biography; list of publications; paper.
  - Particle Physics Group-agendas and memos. (Box-folder F2-13)
  - Particle Physics Report-Physics in the 80's Elementary Particle Physics. Report of the Elementary Particle Physics Panel...1984. (Box-folder F2-14)
  - PAS-PHW, including: (Box-folder F2-15)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: J. Pasupathy.
  - Phi Beta Kappa Scholar-correspondence concerning contributions, information inviting visiting scholars, etc. (Box-folder F2-16)
- Box G1
  - Correspondence about manuscripts and copryrights to/from D. L. Norstrom, Stanley Brown, etc.; scientific papers. (Box-folder G1-1)
  - Copyright forms. (Box-folder G1-2)
  - PHY-PHZ-Physics Today: letters to/from the editor, Gloria Lubkin; articles; American Institute of Physics History Newsletter, May 1989; etc. (Box-folder G1-3)
  - PHY-PHZ-Faculty Meetings-memos, etc. (Box-folder G1-4)
  - PHY-PHZ-General: Physics department reports; data. (Box-folder G1-5)
  - PHY-PHZ-Graduate Committee: questionaire for graduate program; planning for graduate courese; orientation agenda; etc. (Box-folder G1-6)
  - PHY-PHZ-Promotions and Tenure: dossiers in tenure and promotion cases and dossier preparation, etc. (Box-folder G1-7)
  - PHY-PHZ-Review: Report on Assessment of the Physics Department from the Physics Review Committee. (Box-folder G1-8)
  - PHY-PHZ-Astrophysics Group Long Range Planning Report. (Box-folder G1-9)
  - PHY-PHZ-Physics Department Head search: correspondence, etc. (Box-folder G1-10)
  - PHY-PHZ-News: VPI&SU Physics Department News; Annual report for '89-'90. (Box-folder G1-11)
  - PHY-PHZ-Physics Department: report on the plans and strategies for the "longer term," '87. (Box-folder G1-12)
  - PI-POQ-Pisa Conference: Italian Physical Society for the International Conference, 1955-agenda, correspondence. (Box-folder G1-13)
  - POS-PRE-Portugese Agreement; correspondence from: J. M. Araujo, Robert Dyck, etc. (Box-folder G1-14)
  - POS-PRE-Articles published by Pramana. (Box-folder G1-15)
  - POS-PRE-President's House: concerning charge number for certain extension. (Box-folder G1-16)
  - POS-PRE-Presidential Symposium: Atmospheric Carbon Dioxide and Global Warming. (Box-folder G1-17)
  - Pugwash Conference-Pugwash Newsletter, 1982-1987; correspondence from William Swartz. (Box-folder G1-18)
  - PRES-PZ, including: (Box-folder G1-19)
    - 1. Correspondence from Henry Primakoff.
    - 2. Provost-VPI-handwritten notes.
  - R-REP, including: (Box-folder G1-20)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from/about I. I. Rabi; schedule for symposium honoring Rabi.
  - Paper about Frank Quinn's career; correspondence to/from: Roger A. Teekell, Bernard E. La Berge, etc. (Box-folder G1-21)
  - Reports: Education: Education Americans for the 21st Century. (Box-folder G1-22)
  - Research Cooperation correspondence; research project approval; etc. (Box-folder G1-23)
  - REQ-ROL-correspondence to/from: R. Revelle. (Box-folder G1-24)
  - REQ-ROL-Richmond correspondence; report on a conference: The Place of Liberal Arts and Sciences, 1984. (Box-folder G1-25)
  - REQ-ROL-Correspondence to/from/about Thomas Rizzo. (Box-folder G1-26)
  - REQ-ROL-Correspondence to/from: Arthur Roberts. (Box-folder G1-27)
  - REQ-ROL-Correspondence to/from: Don Robson. (Box-folder G1-28)
  - REQ-ROL-Rochester Conference: correspondence to/from: J. McComas; listing sent to P. Gaslion from 1954-1959. (Box-folder G1-29)
  - ROM-RT, including: (Box-folder G1-30)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: L. D. Roper.
    - 2. Correspondence to/from: D. Roselle.
- Box G2
  - RU-RZ, including: (Box-folder G2-1)
    - 1. Russia 1989: correspondence concerning cancellation of Marshak's visit.
    - 2. Russia: concerning budget cuts and denial for a visiting USSR professor.
  - Society of Physics Students (SPS): memo, newsletter. (Box-folder G2-2)
  - Science Research Associates (SRA): correspondence from Richard Giesne, R. D. Bovenschulte, etc. (Box-folder G2-3)
  - SSC [Senate Subcommitte?]: correspondence from Paul Trible, Frederick Boucher, etc. (Box-folder G2-4)
  - Southeastern Universities Research Association (SURA): correspondence from W. E. Lavery, etc. (Box-folder G2-5)
  - S-SAK, including: (Box-folder G2-6)
    - 1. Telegrams and correspondence from R. G. Sachs.
    - 2. SAHEP membership list.
  - Correspondence to/from: Salam. (Box-folder G2-7)
  - SAL-SCHL-Correspondence to/from: Winfield W. Salisbury, Edwin E. Salpeter, etc. (Box-folder G2-8)
  - SCHM-SCIENCE-Correspondence to/from Carl E. Schorske. (Box-folder G2-9)
  - Nomination of S. I. Schwartz to Who's Who, and American Men & Women of Science; correspondence. (Box-folder G2-10)
  - Science, Technology, and Human Values: draft agenda for Task Force on Science Policy. (Box-folder G2-11)
  - Scientists' Institute for Public Information-correspondence to/from: Alan McGowan, Fred Jerome, etc. (Box-folder G2-12)
  - Strategic Arms Limitations Talks (SALT), including: (Box-folder G2-13)
    - 1. Nature of the four fermion interactions: notes, etc.
  - UNESCO paper clippings. (Box-folder G2-14)
- Box H1
  - SCIENTIFIC-SHA, including: (Box-folder H1-1)
    - 1. Correspondence from Carl Shakin, Gino Sengre, etc.
    - 2. Correspondence to/from/about G. Senjanovic.
  - SDI, including: (Box-folder H1-2)
    - 1. Newspaper clippings, articles, and reports.
  - Applications, resumes, and papers for jobs at Virginia Tech in research, associate professor, and assistant professor. (Box-folder H1-3)
  - Search Committee, including: (Box-folder H1-4)
    - 1. Suggested applicants.
    - 2. Search committe for a theoritical particle physicist.
  - Seattle Center, including: (Box-folder H1-5)
    - 1. Concerning the National Theoretical Nuclear Physics Institute.
  - Senior Seminar, including: (Box-folder H1-6)
    - 1. Emerging syntheses in modern science.
    - 2. Santa Fe Institute newsletters, etc.
    - 3. Proposal by Joseph Pitt about emerging synthesis project.
  - SHB-SIK, including: (Box-folder H1-7)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Takeshi Shirafuji, Harold Shimberg, etc.
    - 2. Sigma Xi.
    - 3. Sigma Xi Centennial.
  - SIL-SL, including: (Box-folder H1-8)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Paula Silberstein, Albert Simon, etc.
    - 2. Correspondence to/from: Paul Slattery.
  - Sloan Foundation, including: (Box-folder H1-9)
    - 1. Reports, letters, and suggestions.
    - 2. Lists and letters concerning the Sloan Research Fellows for '68-'69.
    - 3. Sloan program committee.
    - 4. Nominations and eliminations.
    - 5. Meeting of the program committee.
    - 6. The role of the Sloan Foundation.
    - 7, Information and correspondence concerning the foundation.
  - Sloan Foundation, including: (Box-folder H1-10)
    - 1. Letters, name lists, and reports.
  - Sloan Foundation-1970, including: (Box-folder H1-11)
    - 1. Correspondence, reports, nominations, etc.
- Box H2
  - Sloan Foundation, including: (Box-folder H2-1)
    - 1. Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Reports for 1979, 1980, 1981; invites to attend dinners, etc.
  - SM-SP, including: (Box-folder H2-2)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Lloyd P. Smith, Ralph Carlisle Smith, etc.
  - Soviet, including: (Box-folder H2-3)
    - 1. Reports, newsletters, and correspondence from Yori Orlov, concerning the Soviet.
  - Correspondence to/from Gary Staebler. (Box-folder H2-4)
  - STEG-ST, including: (Box-folder H2-5)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: J. Steinberger, Florence Stern, etc.
  - SU-SUZ, including: (Box-folder H2-6)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: E. C. G. Sudarshan.
  - T-TEC, including: (Box-folder H2-7)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: H. Takebe, Igor Tamm (Moscow), etc.
  - Technology and Foreign Affairs, including: (Box-folder H2-8)
    - 1. Symposium on Technology Frontiers and Foreign Relations: program, agenda; listing of attendees; correspondence.
  - TELEX Forms, including: (Box-folder H2-9)
    - 1. Western Union telex forms.
  - TEL-TN, including: (Box-folder H2-10)
    - 1. Correspondence concerning Tiomno Festschrift paper.
    - 2. Correspondence and reports to/from Jayme Tiomno.
  - Correspondence to/from: Y. Tolsa. (Box-folder H2-11)
  - Italy '85, including: (Box-folder H2-12)
    - 1. Approval for travel papers, reimbursement papers.
  - Third World Academy of Science, including: (Box-folder H2-13)
    - 1. Correspondence concerning International Workshop to Assess the Coverage of the Scientific Output of the Third World.
  - TWAS Prize: awards awarded each year; meeting of committees; etc. (Box-folder H2-14)
  - TO-TROV, including: (Box-folder H2-15)
    - 1. TRIUMF program; correspondence concerning the Theory Group at TRIUMF.
  - Trieste, including: (Box-folder H2-16)
    - 1. Correspondence from those unable to attend Trieste Symposium.
    - 2. List of participants attending.
    - 3. Correspondence with Abdus Salam.
  - Trieste, including: (Box-folder H2-17)
    - 1. Participants.
    - 2. Notes, correspondence, and reports.
    - 3. Trieste Center-notes and papers.
    - 4. Correspondence concerning the International Center for Applied Physics (ICAP).
- Box I1
  - Trower, P., including: (Box-folder I1-1)
    - 1. VPI&SU proposal internal approval; proposal to the NSF by W. Peter Trower; correspondence from P. Trower.
  - TROW-TZ, including: (Box-folder I1-2)
    - 1. CV of Hsiung Chia Tze.
  - U, including: (Box-folder I1-3)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: B. M. Udgaonkar, B. A. Uhlendorf; scienctific notes from G. Uhlenbeck.
  - United Nations Educational Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), including: (Box-folder I1-4)
    - 1. Scientific notes, agendas, summary of minutes for the 33rd meeting (1969).
  - UNESCO, including: (Box-folder I1-5)
    - 1. Transcript of proceedings for the 71st executive committee meeting of the U. S. National Commission of UNESCO (1973).
    - 2. Correspondence from John E. Upston, etc.
  - UNESCO, including: (Box-folder I1-6)
    - 1. Newspaper articles (copies); correspondence from Sigvard Eklund; reports and papers by Abdus Salam, etc.
    - 2. Correspondence to Shibli from Abdus Salam; correspondence from people in separated countries (i.e. Brazil, China, etc.).
  - Union of Concerned Scientists, including: (Box-folder I1-7)
    - 1. Correspondence from George Kistiakowsky, etc.
  - University Distinguished Professor, including: (Box-folder I1-8)
    - 1. Correspondence from John D. Wilson, Walk Fabrycky; listing of distinguished professors.
    - 2. President search: Correspondence from Paul Zeifel and Frank Quinn.
  - Lunar Science Institute, including: (Box-folder I1-9)
    - 1. Correspondence from H. M. Van Horn, Robert L. Sproull, etc.
  - Universities Research Association, Inc. (URA) Charter: Bylaws as of July 1, 1968. (Box-folder I1-10)
  - URA, including: (Box-folder I1-11)
    - 1. Notes; correspondence from James C. Matheson, Luke W. Mo; listing of the members of the insitution.
  - V, including: (Box-folder I1-12)
    - 1. Visitors-Correspondence concerning visits and invites from Zhao Zhi-yong, T. E. Gilmer, Jr., etc.
    - 2. Visitors-People interested in visiting VPI.
  - VPI&SU, including: (Box-folder I1-13)
    - 1. 1983 Faculty Handbook; newsletter; interim report; procedural guidelines; policies and procedures from grad school, 1987-88.
    - 2. Correspondence/Memorandums to/from: George Crofts, etc.
  - VPI Development, including: (Box-folder I1-14)
    - 1. VPI Panel Discussion-correpondence concerning the 1984 Fall Administrator Conference.
    - 2. Research opportunities.
  - VPI, including: (Box-folder I1-15)
    - 1. Correspondence fom Donald Nurse concerning program for gifted high school students, a VPI school of science.
- Box I2
  - Von Humboldt-Stifling Award, including: (Box-folder I2-1)
    - 1. Awards for Senior U. S. Scientist.
  - W-WAS, including: (Box-folder I2-2)
    - 1. Letters to/from: James Wadsworth, Ivar Waller, etc.
    - 2. Letters to/from/about: Ping Wang.
  - Washington Hotels, including: (Box-folder I2-3)
    - 1. Brief list of hotels in D. C.
  - Washington Reporters' Seminar. (Box-folder I2-4)
  - WAT-WE, including: (Box-folder I2-5)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Steven Weinberg, Charles Weiss, Jr., etc.
    - 2. Letters to/from Victor Weisskopf.
    - 3. Weisskopf visits.
  - Weapons in Space (Panel Discussion). (Box-folder I2-6)
  - WF-WILE, including: (Box-folder I2-7)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: John Wheeler, Milton White, etc.
  - WILF-WILSON, including: (Box-folder I2-8)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: David Wilkinson, Franklin Williams, etc.
    - 2. Correspondence from John Wilson.
  - Correspondence to/from Richard Wilson. (Box-folder I2-9)
  - Wilson, Robert R., including: (Box-folder I2-10)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from R. R. Wilson.
    - 2. Proposal for a 10 gev electron synchtron at Cornell.
  - Correspondence concerning the World University. (Box-folder I2-11)
  - WIM-WZ, including: (Box-folder I2-12)
    - 1. Correspondence from Lincoln Wolfenstein, A. Wishart, etc.
    - 2. Wood hole (VHEA).
  - X, including: (Box-folder I2-13)
    - 1. Corerspondence from Xerox Corp, Dong Fang Xiau, etc.
  - Y, including: (Box-folder I2-14)
    - 1. Correspondence from Fujia Yang, Herbert York, etc.
  - Z, including: (Box-folder I2-15)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Walter Zablocke, Zhao Zhi-yong.
    - 2. Correspondnece to/from/about P. E. Zweifel.
- Box J1
  - AAP (American Institute of Science), including: (Box-folder J1-1)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Gloria B. Lubkin, Norman F. Ramsey, Spencer Wert, etc.
    - 2. Center for History of Physics Archives: correspondence to/from John N. Warnow.
    - 3. Weiner Interview: correspondence with Spencer R. Wert, Charles Weiner interview of Marshak.
    - 4. Niels Bohr Library/American Institute of Physics Newsletter.
  - American Institute of Physics (AIP), including: (Box-folder J1-2)
    - 1. Correspondence from Joan Warnow, Charles Weiner, etc.
    - 2. American Institute of Physics Annual Report 1966.
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, including: (Box-folder J1-3)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from Michael J. Moravcsik, Michel Baranger, etc.
    - 2. Article by S. L. Quimby on the future organization of the American Physical Society.
  - APS, including: 1968. (Box-folder J1-4)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from: Shelley M. Mark, R. C. Desai, etc.
    - 2. Participants of the World Meeting.
  - Awards, including: (Box-folder J1-5)
    - 1. 1985 APKER Award nominees.
    - 2. Correspondence of nominations.
  - APS, including: (Box-folder J1-6)
    - 1. 7 envelopes addressed to the American Physical Society.
    - 2. Correspondence from John C. Crowley, 1982 Council and committees on the American Physical Society.
    - 3. 1982 nominating committee.
  - Bickford, L., including: (Box-folder J1-7)
    - Correspondence from George M. Woodwell.
  - APS Brazil, including: (Box-folder J1-8)
    - Trip report to Brazil 1983.
  - Burton, J., including: (Box-folder J1-9)
    - 1. Correspondence to/from Joseph Burton.
    - 2. Letters to/from Sakurai.
  - CAP, including: (Box-folder J1-10)
    - Correspondence from H. D. Keith.
  - CESSE-APS, including: (Box-folder J1-11)